Guide to the Ladislas Segoe and Associates, City Planners Records, 1924-1966
Segoe, Ladislas and Associates City Planners Records, 1924-1966
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ladislas Segoe and Associates, City Planners records, 1924-1966
2789
Ladislas Segoe and Associates, City Planners.
24.6 cubic ft., 2 volumes.
Reports, master plans, correspondence, job files, tape recordings, and a transcript.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes reports, master plans, correspondence, and job files of Ladislas Segoe and Associates of Cincinnati, Ohio; and reports of the National Resources Committee (1937-1939). Master plans for Ohio cities, especially Cincinnati and Dayton; and many other areas. Correspondence regarding the Tennessee Valley Authority, Ohio State Planning Board, and Kentucky State Planning Board; and correspondence and job files concerning Greenville, Ohio. Also, tape recordings and published transcript of interview with Ladislas Segoe by Sydney H. Williams, May 1978.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes reports, master plans, correspondence, and job files of Ladislas Segoe and Associates of Cincinnati, Ohio; and reports of the National Resources Committee (1937-1939). Master plans for Ohio cities, especially Cincinnati and Dayton; and many other areas, including Ashland, Kentucky; Charleston, West Virginia; Frederick, Maryland; Lansing and Detroit, Michigan; and Wayne County, Indiana. Correspondence regarding the Tennessee Valley Authority, Ohio State Planning Board, and Kentucky State Planning Board; and correspondence and job files concerning Greenville, Ohio. Also, tape recordings and published transcript of interview with Ladislas Segoe by Sydney H. Williams, May 1978.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ladislas Segoe and Associates, City Planners.; Segoe, Ladislas.; Williams, Sydney H., interviewer.; Kentucky. State Planning Board.; Ohio. State Planning Board.; Tennessee Valley Authority.; United States. National Resources Committee.
Subjects:
City planning.; City planning--Ohio.
Places:
Ashland (Ky.)--City planning.; Charleston (W. Va.)--City planning.; Cincinnati (Ohio)--City planning.; Dayton (Ohio)--City planning.; Detroit (Mich.)--City planning.; Frederick (Md.)--City planning.; Greenville (Ohio)--City planning.; Lansing (Mich.)--City planning.; Wayne County (Ind.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Urbanism--technical monographs (Box 1-5)
- Interprofessional Urban Planning Committee, 1 f.f. (Box 3)
- Urbanism Study--files (Box 6)
- National Resources Planning Board (Box 7)
- National Resources Committee including folders on Indiana (Box 8)
- National Resources Committee--reports, monographs, plus some correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 9-10)
- Master plan for development of Howe Smith properties, Consolidated Toronto Development Corp. Ltd., January 1955 (Box 11)
- Ohio State Planning Board Reports; local planning administration reports; low-cost housing and slum clearance project, Cincinnati, Ohio; the Oakland Study--Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1950 (Box 11)
- Centennial Competition for a plan for Redevelopment and Improvement of the Central Commercial District of Chicago--Carson, Pirie, Scott & Co., 1954 (Box 11)
- pamphlets related to planning; Metropolitan Data Center project, March 1, 1965 (Box 11)
- Local planning adm. drafts and related correspondence (Box 12-13)
- General correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 14)
- Covington, Ky. correspondence, 1931-1940 (Box 14)
- Lexington, Ky. correspondence, 1928-1932 (Box 14)
- Columbus, Ohio correspondence and county zoning bill (old) (Box 14)
- Institute of Traffic Engineers correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 15)
- Tennessee Valley Authority correspondence, 1934-1946 (Box 15)
- Hamilton County Regional Planning, 1929-1930, 1931-1934 (Box 15)
- Laurel Homes Redevelopment, 1930-1931 (Box 15)
- Cincinnati Union Terminal; Covington, Ky., 1929-1931 (Box 16)
- Dayton, Ohio, 1925-1930 (Box 16)
- Toronto, Canada, Switchyard Study; Tucson, Arizona, Comprehensive Plan Reports, 1936 (Box 17)
- Rehabilitation of Blighted Areas and Conservation of Sound Neighbors; Louisville, Ky., Traffic Survey, 1926-1929 (Box 17)
- Comprehensive Master Plan for Madison, Wisconsin and its Environs; Second Inter-American Congress of Municipalities, Santiago, Chile, 1941 (Box 17)
- Ladislas Segoe's speeches and papers (1 envelope) (Box 17)
- Ohio State Planning Board, correspondence, 1934-1936 (Box 18)
- Ohio State Planning Conference; Ohio State Planning Board, reports, activities, etc., 1934-1937 (Box 18)
- Ohio Valley Regional Planning Commission, 1936-1937 (Box 18)
- Correspondence, reports, meetings (Box 18)
- Dayton, Ohio Comprehensive Plan; Greenville files; Madeira, Ohio, Jonas B. Frenkel, Davis Betts, National Safety Council; Middletown, Ohio, 1930 (Box 19)
- Niagara Falls, Oakwood, Ohio, reports, correspondence, bills, zoning ordinances; Indian Hill Comprehensive Plan (Ohio) (Box 20)
- Piqua, Ohio, correspondence, bills, contracts; Kentucky State Planning Board correspondence (old); Louisville Traffic Survey; Woodside Homes (Box 21)
- Our Cities--National Resources Committee, 1937 (Box 22)
- Urban Planning and Land Policies--National Resources Committee, vols. I-II, 1939 (Box 22)
- Ashland, Kentucky Comprehensive Master Plan, 1959 (Box 22)
- Bellaire, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1963 (Box 22)
- Bellefontaine, Ohio City Plan, 1956 (Box 22)
- Cahokia, Illinois Comprehensive Master Plan, 1966 (Box 22)
- Charleston, W. Va. Comprehensive Master Plan, vols. I-II, 1962 (Box 22)
- Chillicothe, Ohio Master Plan, 1949 (Box 22)
- Chillicothe, Ohio Master Plan (revised), 1960 (Box 22)
- Cincinnati, Ohio--Official plan, 1925 (Box 22)
  - Metropolitan Master Plan studies (monographs)
    - Airports, 1946
    - Economy of the area, 1946
    - Industrial areas, 1946
    - Motorways, 1947
    - Parking, 1947
    - Population, 1945
    - Public service facilities, 1947
    - Public transit, 1946
    - Recreation, 1947
    - Residential areas, 1946
    - Riverfront development, 1946
  - Riverfront redevelopment plan, 1946
  - Statement and evidence submitted on pending zoning ordinance, 1924
  - Zoning ordinance outline, 1958
- Columbus, Indiana--A renewal action program, 1961 (Box 22)
- Coshocton, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1961 (Box 22)
- Covington, Kentucky Comprehensive Master Plan, 1931 (Box 22)
- Dayton, Ohio (Box 22)
  - Dayton, Ohio and Its City Plan (brochure), 1930
  - Grade crossing elimination, 1925
- Delaware, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1964 (Box 22)
- Delaware County, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1964 (Box 22)
- Detroit, Michigan (Box 22-23)
  - Master Plan (oversize, loose on shelf), 1951
  - Expressway and Transit System (oversize, loose on shelf), 1945
  - Master Plan (brochures):
    - Development of Riverfront, 1945
    - Land Use Plan, 1947
    - Recreational Facilities, 1946
    - Trafficways, 1946
- Elmwood Place, Ohio General, 1964 (Box 23)
- Fayette County, Ohio General Plan, 1964 (Box 23)
- Franklin, Ohio (Box 23)
  - Comprehensive Development Plan, 1966
  - Report on Plan Effectuation and Review, 1966
  - Capital Improvements Program, 1966
- Frederick, Maryland Comprehensive Plan, 1964 (Box 23)
- Granville, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1964 (Box 23)
- Greenville, Ohio City Plan, 1945 (Box 23)
- Guernsey County, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1965 (Box 23)
- Hamilton County, Ohio Report on Main Thoroughfares, 1936 (Box 23)
- Heath, Ohio Community Plan, 1963 (Box 23)
- Kanawha County, W. Va. Comprehensive Metropolitan Plan, vols. I-II, 1964 (Box 23)
- Kenton, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1964 (Box 23)
- Lansing, Michigan Comprehensive Master Plan, 1958 (Box 23)
- Lawrenceburg, Indiana Comprehensive Master Plan, 1965 (Box 23)
- Lexington, Ky. Comprehensive Plan, 1931 (Box 23)
- Louisville, Ky. Traffic Survey, vols. I-II, 1927 (Box 23)
- Mason, Ohio Master Plan, 1963 (Box 24)
- Newark, Ohio (Box 24)
  - Comprehensive Master Plan, 1964
  - Supporting documentation--Vol. II, 1964
- North College Hill, Ohio Comprehensive Development Plan, 1966 (Box 24)
- Norwalk, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1964 (Box 24)
- Oconomowoc, Wisconsin City Plan, 1957 (Box 24)
- Richmond, Indiana Comprehensive Master Plan and Appendix, 1966 (Box 24)
- Richmond, Virginia Land Use and Community Facilities, 1951 (Box 24)
- Rock Island, Illinois (Box 24)
  - City Plan, 1958
  - Extension of Comprehensive City Plan, 1958
- St. Albans, West Virginia City Plan, 1953 (Box 24)
- St. Bernard, Ohio General Community Plan, 1964 (Box 24)
- San Francisco, California (Box 24)
  - Redevelopment Study, 1947
  - New City--San Francisco Redeveloped, 1947
  - Transportation Plan, 1948
- Springfield, Missouri (Box 24)
  - Master Plan for Commercial Development, 1964
  - Supporting Documentation, 1964
- Tuscon, Arizona Rehabilitation of Blighted Areas--Conservation of Sound Neighborhoods, 1942 (Box 24)
- Tulsa, Oklahoma Program for Community Renewal, 1963 (Box 24)
- Washington, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, 1962 (Box 24)
- Wayne County, Indiana Comprehensive Master Plan, 1966 (Box 24)
- Zanesville, Ohio Comprehensive Master Plan, vols. I-II, 1963 (Box 24)
- Interviews with Ladislas Segoe (3 tape recordings - tr-10504, tr-10505, tr-10506), 1978 (Box 25)
  -contents of recordings have been digitized and placed on DVD-1323, which is also located in this box
- Transcript of interviews with Ladislas Segoe, 1978 (Box 25)
- "The Development of the Practitioner's Art: Ladislas Segoe, 1921-1968", by David J. Allor and Elizabeth D. Byrne (Box 25)
- City plan, Newport, Kentucky, 1947 (Box 25)
- Master Plan, Winona Minnesota, 1959 (Box 26)
- Comprehensive Master Plan, Flint Michigan, 1960 (Box 26)